

Ramin Rezaei

Front-end Engineer

CONTACT

<u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Stack Overflow</u> | <u>Personal Website</u>
Tehran, Iran | <u>+989136266179</u> | <u>Ramin.Rezaei77@gmail.com</u>

SUMMARY

I used to be a graphic designer but then I fell in love with programming. I am currently a **front-end engineer** with more than **4 years** of experience and a little bit of back-end development. And now I work for **Digikala**. which is the largest online store in Iran with about **9 million visits per day**. Digikala is an Iranian example for Amazon.

I also used to work at **SnappCarFix**, an online platform for auto parts and services powered by **Snapp** (an Uber clone).

SKILLS

- → Front-end: **JavaScript**, **ReactJS**, Html, CSS, SASS, LESS, Tailwind, NextJs, TypeScript, StoryBook, Jest, Cypress, A/B testing, JQuery, and familiar with VueJs.
- → Back-end: **Python** (Django), SQL, MySQL, Rest API, Docker.
- → Others: Git, Linux OS, Scrum, Trunk-based Development (TBD), GitFlow.

GRAPHIC SKILLS

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe AfterEffects, Adobe Premiere Pro, Motion Graphic Animation, Video Editing. Also, I am familiar with: Cinema 4D, AutoDesk 3Ds Max, Adobe XS, Figma, and Zeplin.

EXPERIENCE

Digikala, Tehran, Iran — Front-end Engineer

Aug 2020 - Present

Skills: JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJs, NextJs, Redux, Tailwind, SASS, StoryBook, Jest, Cypress, Formik, A/B tests

- Worked in a highly collaborative agile team environment with more than 50 people in different teams.
- Wrote unit tests for basic tools and components with joke and react-testing-library, which reduced reported bugs and errors by 30% in one month.
- Wrote end-to-end (E2E) tests for the main flows on the site like add-to-cart, and payment with Cypress.
- Proposing and creating a service with a new and fast algorithm to track user behavior with products and banners on the site, which made the information tracked 90% more accurately.
- Invented a new pattern for the API structure presented in the project, which makes changes in a large system 50% safer.
- It has developed a service to automatically show and hide different features and sections of the site in trial and production versions, which is applicable in promotions and even for a certain number of users.

- Reducing the reuse of Google Analytics codes and functions by 80% by writing a wrapper and using functions at the lowest level of components.
- 10% improvement in product page load speed and 30% reduction in API requests by caching data, reusing static information, and removing static requests.
- Increased website view limit by 5x in promotions by rewriting the website with react.
- Reduced bundle size by half due to tree shaking and rewrote of 3rd party libraries.
- 50% performance increase in tracking user behavior with products and banners inside the site.
- Reviewed the code of at least 3 team members daily and recommended changes to improve code quality.

SnappCarFix, Esfahan, Iran — Head of Front-end Team

May 2019 - Aug 2020

Skills: JavaScript, ReactJs, Redux, SASS, AntDesign, Google Map, MapBox

- Created 4 progressive web applications and two admin dashboards.
- Using Google Recaptcha to authenticate users of 3 sites with different applications and using JWT and refresh token in front-end requests.
- The standard version (x,y,z) was used for projects, and the automatic update of the client-side cache, which in the long run improved the process of product development and updating by 20%.
- Designing a single layout for the organization's sales sites. Using this template, you can create a completely new site in just 24 hours.
- Grown the Lottie animations performance by 80% by developing a new wrapper.
- The correct use of CSS animation and the correct animation of elements on the web raised the loading speed by 50% and no lag was observed in the mobile version.
- 60% improvement in SwiperJs performance by writing a wrapper in the project and using it a lot in the whole project without loss of performance.
- Making high-performance and high-use timer parts for advertisements and discount banners on the site, which improved the site load time by 2 seconds.
- Rebuilt the platform from WordPress to React and made more requests with better UI/UX and fewer development hassles resulting in a 90% improvement in user experience.

Self-Employed, Esfahan, Iran — *Freelance*

Jan 2019 - Present

Skills: JavaScript, ReactJs, Tailwind, SASS, Jest, Python (Django)
Graphic Skills: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Premiere Pro

- Building short videos of product advertisements for more than 4 companies.
- I have been able to produce more than 10 video Ads and motion graphics animations.
- So far, I designed and implemented 3 web platforms for club management and product sales, which keep been running for more than 3 years.
- Creating more than 12 landing pages for events and promotions.

EDUCATION

Najaf Abad University, Isfahan — Bachelor's degree

Sep 2016 - Sep 2021

LANGUAGES

Persian - Native

English - General level